<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="27.689" dur="7">It is a rare honor in this life to follow
one of your heroes. And John Lewis is one</text><text start="40.1" dur="7">of my heroes.
Now, I have to imagine that when a younger</text><text start="48.899" dur="7">John Lewis woke up that morning fifty years
ago and made his way to Brown Chapel, heroics</text><text start="60.98" dur="7">were not on his mind. A day like this was
not on his mind. Young folks with bedrolls</text><text start="73.03" dur="7">and backpacks were milling about. Veterans
of the movement trained newcomers in the tactics</text><text start="81.45" dur="7">of non-violence; the right way to protect
yourself when attacked. A doctor described</text><text start="90.1" dur="6.719">what tear gas does to the body, while marchers
scribbled down instructions for contacting</text><text start="96.819" dur="7">their loved ones. The air was thick with doubt,
anticipation, and fear. They comforted themselves</text><text start="110.91" dur="5.319">with the final verse of the final hymn they
sung:</text><text start="116.229" dur="7">No matter what may be the test, God will take
care of you;</text><text start="124" dur="7">Lean, weary one, upon His breast, God will
take care of you.</text><text start="132.33" dur="7">Then, his knapsack stocked with an apple,
a toothbrush, a book on government – all</text><text start="142.23" dur="7">you need for a night behind bars – John
Lewis led them out of the church on a mission</text><text start="150.73" dur="7">to change America.
President Bush and Mrs. Bush, Governor Bentley,</text><text start="168.819" dur="7">Members of Congress, Mayor Evans, Reverend
Strong, friends and fellow Americans:</text><text start="182.25" dur="7">There are places, and moments in America where
this nation’s destiny has been decided.</text><text start="190.819" dur="7">Many are sites of war – Concord and Lexington,
Appomattox and Gettysburg. Others are sites</text><text start="200.6" dur="7">that symbolize the daring of America’s character
– Independence Hall and Seneca Falls, Kitty</text><text start="209.66" dur="7">Hawk and Cape Canaveral.
Selma is such a place.</text><text start="219.02" dur="7">In one afternoon fifty years ago, so much
of our turbulent history – the stain of</text><text start="228.74" dur="7">slavery and anguish of civil war; the yoke
of segregation and tyranny of Jim Crow; the</text><text start="238.86" dur="7">death of four little girls in Birmingham,
and the dream of a Baptist preacher – met</text><text start="247.239" dur="7">on this bridge.
It was not a clash of armies, but a clash</text><text start="254.91" dur="7">of wills; a contest to determine the meaning
of America.</text><text start="264.46" dur="7">And because of men and women like John Lewis,
Joseph Lowery, Hosea Williams, Amelia Boynton,</text><text start="277.21" dur="7">Diane Nash, Ralph Abernathy, C.T. Vivian,
Andrew Young, Fred Shuttlesworth, Dr. King,</text><text start="286.83" dur="7">and so many more, the idea of a just America,
a fair America, an inclusive America, a generous</text><text start="297.16" dur="7">America – that idea ultimately triumphed.
As is true across the landscape of American</text><text start="308.38" dur="7">history, we cannot examine this moment in
isolation. The march on Selma was part of</text><text start="315.55" dur="7">a broader campaign that spanned generations;
the leaders that day part of a long line of</text><text start="322.85" dur="7">heroes.
We gather here to celebrate them. We gather</text><text start="331.24" dur="6.73">here to honor the courage of ordinary Americans
willing to endure billy clubs and the chastening</text><text start="337.97" dur="6.41">rod; tear gas and the trampling hoof; men
and women who despite the gush of blood and</text><text start="344.38" dur="6.25">splintered bone would stay true to their North
Star and keep marching toward justice.</text><text start="350.63" dur="7">They did as Scripture instructed: “Rejoice
in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant</text><text start="362.699" dur="7">in prayer.” And in the days to come, they
went back again and again. When the trumpet</text><text start="372.58" dur="7">call sounded for more to join, the people
came – black and white, young and old, Christian</text><text start="381.46" dur="7">and Jew, waving the American flag and singing
the same anthems full of faith and hope. A</text><text start="390.96" dur="7">white newsman, Bill Plante, who covered the
marches then and who is with us here today,</text><text start="398.99" dur="7">quipped that the growing number of white people
lowered the quality of the singing. To those</text><text start="408.12" dur="6.45">who marched, though, those old gospel songs
must have never sounded so sweet.</text><text start="414.57" dur="7">In time, their chorus would reach President
Johnson. And he would send them protection,</text><text start="429.38" dur="5.14">echoing their call for the nation and the
world to hear:</text><text start="434.52" dur="7">“We shall overcome.”
What enormous faith these men and women had.</text><text start="448.35" dur="7">Faith in God – but also faith in America.
The Americans who crossed this bridge were</text><text start="456.59" dur="7">not physically imposing. But they gave courage
to millions. They held no elected office.</text><text start="466.039" dur="7">But they led a nation. They marched as Americans
who had endured hundreds of years of brutal</text><text start="473.71" dur="6.179">violence, and countless daily indignities
– but they didn’t seek special treatment,</text><text start="479.889" dur="7">just the equal treatment promised to them
almost a century before.</text><text start="489.53" dur="6.49">What they did here will reverberate through
the ages. Not because the change they won</text><text start="496.02" dur="7">was preordained; not because their victory
was complete; but because they proved that</text><text start="506.55" dur="7">nonviolent change is possible; that love and
hope can conquer hate.</text><text start="518.789" dur="4.72">As we commemorate their achievement, we are
well-served to remember that at the time of</text><text start="523.509" dur="7">the marches, many in power condemned rather
than praised them. Back then, they were called</text><text start="531.959" dur="7">Communists, half-breeds, outside agitators,
sexual and moral degenerates, and worse – everything</text><text start="542.55" dur="7">but the name their parents gave them. Their
faith was questioned. Their lives were threatened.</text><text start="552.32" dur="7">Their patriotism was challenged.
And yet, what could be more American than</text><text start="559.66" dur="7">what happened in this place?
What could more profoundly vindicate the idea</text><text start="570.41" dur="7">of America than plain and humble people – the
unsung, the downtrodden, the dreamers not</text><text start="579.25" dur="7">of high station, not born to wealth or privilege,
not of one religious tradition but many – coming</text><text start="586.37" dur="7">together to shape their country’s course?
What greater expression of faith in the American</text><text start="593.5" dur="6.68">experiment than this; what greater form of
patriotism is there; than the belief that</text><text start="600.18" dur="7">America is not yet finished, that we are strong
enough to be self-critical, that each successive</text><text start="607.42" dur="5.22">generation can look upon our imperfections
and decide that it is in our power to remake</text><text start="612.64" dur="6.15">this nation to more closely align with our
highest ideals?</text><text start="618.79" dur="7">That’s why Selma is not some outlier in
the American experience. That’s why it’s</text><text start="630.54" dur="7">not a museum or static monument to behold
from a distance. It is instead the manifestation</text><text start="638.31" dur="7">of a creed written into our founding documents:
“We the People…in order to form a more</text><text start="645.85" dur="6.01">perfect union.”
“We hold these truths to be self-evident,</text><text start="651.86" dur="7">that all men are created equal.”
These are not just words. They are a living</text><text start="661" dur="7">thing, a call to action, a roadmap for citizenship
and an insistence in the capacity of free</text><text start="669.49" dur="7">men and women to shape our own destiny. For
founders like Franklin and Jefferson, for</text><text start="677.14" dur="5.62">leaders like Lincoln and FDR, the success
of our experiment in self-government rested</text><text start="682.76" dur="6.8">on engaging all our citizens in this work.
That’s what we celebrate here in Selma.</text><text start="689.56" dur="7">That’s what this movement was all about,
one leg in our long journey toward freedom.</text><text start="699.83" dur="7">The American instinct that led these young
men and women to pick up the torch and cross</text><text start="708.089" dur="5.571">this bridge is the same instinct that moved
patriots to choose revolution over tyranny.</text><text start="713.66" dur="5.95">It’s the same instinct that drew immigrants
from across oceans and the Rio Grande; the</text><text start="719.61" dur="4.49">same instinct that led women to reach for
the ballot and workers to organize against</text><text start="724.1" dur="6.45">an unjust status quo; the same instinct that
led us to plant a flag at Iwo Jima and on</text><text start="730.55" dur="7">the surface of the Moon.
It’s the idea held by generations of citizens</text><text start="737.98" dur="5.299">who believed that America is a constant work
in progress; who believed that loving this</text><text start="743.279" dur="6.821">country requires more than singing its praises
or avoiding uncomfortable truths. It requires</text><text start="750.1" dur="5.6">the occasional disruption, the willingness
to speak out for what’s right and shake</text><text start="755.7" dur="7">up the status quo.
That’s what makes us unique, and cements</text><text start="769.18" dur="6.42">our reputation as a beacon of opportunity.
Young people behind the Iron Curtain would</text><text start="775.6" dur="6.31">see Selma and eventually tear down a wall.
Young people in Soweto would hear Bobby Kennedy</text><text start="781.91" dur="6.429">talk about ripples of hope and eventually
banish the scourge of apartheid. Young people</text><text start="788.339" dur="7">in Burma went to prison rather than submit
to military rule. From the streets of Tunis</text><text start="797.399" dur="6.141">to the Maidan in Ukraine, this generation
of young people can draw strength from this</text><text start="803.54" dur="6.7">place, where the powerless could change the
world’s greatest superpower, and push their</text><text start="810.24" dur="7">leaders to expand the boundaries of freedom.
They saw that idea made real in Selma, Alabama.</text><text start="819.54" dur="7">They saw it made real in America.
Because of campaigns like this, a Voting Rights</text><text start="830.74" dur="7">Act was passed. Political, economic, and social
barriers came down, and the change these men</text><text start="838.529" dur="4.151">and women wrought is visible here today in
the presence of African-Americans who run</text><text start="842.68" dur="6.19">boardrooms, who sit on the bench, who serve
in elected office from small towns to big</text><text start="848.87" dur="7">cities; from the Congressional Black Caucus
to the Oval Office.</text><text start="857.5" dur="6.88">Because of what they did, the doors of opportunity
swung open not just for African-Americans,</text><text start="864.38" dur="6.68">but for every American. Women marched through
those doors. Latinos marched through those</text><text start="871.06" dur="6.85">doors. Asian-Americans, gay Americans, and
Americans with disabilities came through those</text><text start="877.91" dur="7">doors. Their endeavors gave the entire South
the chance to rise again, not by reasserting</text><text start="890.76" dur="7">the past, but by transcending the past.
What a glorious thing, Dr. King might say.</text><text start="899.94" dur="7">What a solemn debt we owe.
Which leads us to ask, just how might we repay</text><text start="908.48" dur="5.94">that debt?
First and foremost, we have to recognize that</text><text start="914.42" dur="7">one day’s commemoration, no matter how special,
is not enough. If Selma taught us anything,</text><text start="924.44" dur="7">it’s that our work is never done – the
American experiment in self-government gives</text><text start="931.67" dur="7">work and purpose to each generation.
Selma teaches us, too, that action requires</text><text start="940.57" dur="7">that we shed our cynicism. For when it comes
to the pursuit of justice, we can afford neither</text><text start="948.529" dur="7">complacency nor despair.
Just this week, I was asked whether I thought</text><text start="955.68" dur="4.839">the Department of Justice’s Ferguson report
shows that, with respect to race, little has</text><text start="960.519" dur="7">changed in this country. I understand the
question, for the report’s narrative was</text><text start="968.519" dur="7">woefully familiar. It evoked the kind of abuse
and disregard for citizens that spawned the</text><text start="976.8" dur="7">Civil Rights Movement. But I rejected the
notion that nothing’s changed. What happened</text><text start="985.149" dur="5.521">in Ferguson may not be unique, but it’s
no longer endemic, or sanctioned by law and</text><text start="990.67" dur="6.07">custom; and before the Civil Rights Movement,
it most surely was.</text><text start="996.74" dur="5.67">We do a disservice to the cause of justice
by intimating that bias and discrimination</text><text start="1002.41" dur="6.72">are immutable, or that racial division is
inherent to America. If you think nothing’s</text><text start="1009.13" dur="4.68">changed in the past fifty years, ask somebody
who lived through the Selma or Chicago or</text><text start="1013.81" dur="7">L.A. of the Fifties. Ask the female CEO who
once might have been assigned to the secretarial</text><text start="1022.26" dur="6.049">pool if nothing’s changed. Ask your gay
friend if it’s easier to be out and proud</text><text start="1028.309" dur="7">in America now than it was thirty years ago.
To deny this progress – our progress – would</text><text start="1039.85" dur="7">be to rob us of our own agency; our responsibility
to do what we can to make America better.</text><text start="1050.97" dur="7">Of course, a more common mistake is to suggest
that racism is banished, that the work that</text><text start="1061.47" dur="5.209">drew men and women to Selma is complete, and
that whatever racial tensions remain are a</text><text start="1066.679" dur="7">consequence of those seeking to play the “race
card” for their own purposes. We don’t</text><text start="1074.009" dur="6.321">need the Ferguson report to know that’s
not true. We just need to open our eyes, and</text><text start="1080.33" dur="4.689">ears, and hearts, to know that this nation’s
racial history still casts its long shadow</text><text start="1085.019" dur="7">upon us. We know the march is not yet over,
the race is not yet won, and that reaching</text><text start="1097.33" dur="6.059">that blessed destination where we are judged
by the content of our character – requires</text><text start="1103.389" dur="7">admitting as much.
“We are capable of bearing a great burden,”</text><text start="1113.6" dur="7">James Baldwin wrote, “once we discover that
the burden is reality and arrive where reality</text><text start="1122.919" dur="7">is.”
This is work for all Americans, and not just</text><text start="1134.779" dur="7">some. Not just whites. Not just blacks. If
we want to honor the courage of those who</text><text start="1142.009" dur="6.681">marched that day, then all of us are called
to possess their moral imagination. All of</text><text start="1148.69" dur="5.959">us will need to feel, as they did, the fierce
urgency of now. All of us need to recognize,</text><text start="1154.649" dur="7">as they did, that change depends on our actions,
our attitudes, the things we teach our children.</text><text start="1163.109" dur="7">And if we make such effort, no matter how
hard it may seem, laws can be passed, and</text><text start="1174.229" dur="7">consciences can be stirred, and consensus
can be built.</text><text start="1182.229" dur="5.03">With such effort, we can make sure our criminal
justice system serves all and not just some.</text><text start="1187.259" dur="4.25">Together, we can raise the level of mutual
trust that policing is built on – the idea</text><text start="1191.509" dur="6.13">that police officers are members of the communities
they risk their lives to protect, and citizens</text><text start="1197.639" dur="3.821">in Ferguson and New York and Cleveland just
want the same thing young people here marched</text><text start="1201.46" dur="7">for – the protection of the law. Together,
we can address unfair sentencing, and overcrowded</text><text start="1213.84" dur="5.789">prisons, and the stunted circumstances that
rob too many boys of the chance to become</text><text start="1219.629" dur="7">men, and rob the nation of too many men who
could be good dads, and workers, and neighbors.</text><text start="1231.34" dur="6.74">With effort, we can roll back poverty and
the roadblocks to opportunity. Americans don’t</text><text start="1238.08" dur="6.599">accept a free ride for anyone, nor do we believe
in equality of outcomes. But we do expect</text><text start="1244.679" dur="7">equal opportunity, and if we really mean it,
if we’re willing to sacrifice for it, then</text><text start="1253.409" dur="5.47">we can make sure every child gets an education
suitable to this new century, one that expands</text><text start="1258.879" dur="7">imaginations and lifts their sights and gives
them skills. We can make sure every person</text><text start="1266.359" dur="5.75">willing to work has the dignity of a job,
and a fair wage, and a real voice, and sturdier</text><text start="1272.109" dur="7">rungs on that ladder into the middle class.
And with effort, we can protect the foundation</text><text start="1281.239" dur="5.87">stone of our democracy for which so many marched
across this bridge – and that is the right</text><text start="1287.109" dur="7">to vote. Right now, in 2015, fifty years after
Selma, there are laws across this country</text><text start="1304.529" dur="7">designed to make it harder for people to vote.
As we speak, more of such laws are being proposed.</text><text start="1313.58" dur="7">Meanwhile, the Voting Rights Act, the culmination
of so much blood and sweat and tears, the</text><text start="1321.669" dur="7">product of so much sacrifice in the face of
wanton violence, stands weakened, its future</text><text start="1330.82" dur="7">subject to partisan rancor.
How can that be? The Voting Rights Act was</text><text start="1340.419" dur="7">one of the crowning achievements of our democracy,
the result of Republican and Democratic effort.</text><text start="1349.529" dur="5.311">President Reagan signed its renewal when he
was in office. President Bush signed its renewal</text><text start="1354.84" dur="5.019">when he was in office. One hundred Members
of Congress have come here today to honor</text><text start="1359.859" dur="5.99">people who were willing to die for the right
it protects. If we want to honor this day,</text><text start="1365.849" dur="5.76">let these hundred go back to Washington, and
gather four hundred more, and together, pledge</text><text start="1371.609" dur="7">to make it their mission to restore the law
this year.</text><text start="1389.22" dur="7">Of course, our democracy is not the task of
Congress alone, or the courts alone, or the</text><text start="1397.149" dur="7">President alone. If every new voter suppression
law was struck down today, we’d still have</text><text start="1408.239" dur="7">one of the lowest voting rates among free
peoples. Fifty years ago, registering to vote</text><text start="1415.539" dur="5.21">here in Selma and much of the South meant
guessing the number of jellybeans in a jar</text><text start="1420.749" dur="6.341">or bubbles on a bar of soap. It meant risking
your dignity, and sometimes, your life. What</text><text start="1427.09" dur="7">is our excuse today for not voting? How do
we so casually discard the right for which</text><text start="1436.909" dur="7">so many fought? How do we so fully give away
our power, our voice, in shaping America’s</text><text start="1449.269" dur="7">future?
Fellow marchers, so much has changed in fifty</text><text start="1466.789" dur="7">years. We’ve endured war, and fashioned
peace. We’ve seen technological wonders</text><text start="1475.929" dur="6.24">that touch every aspect of our lives, and
take for granted convenience our parents might</text><text start="1482.169" dur="7">scarcely imagine. But what has not changed
is the imperative of citizenship, that willingness</text><text start="1492.249" dur="7">of a 26 year-old deacon, or a Unitarian minister,
or a young mother of five, to decide they</text><text start="1499.499" dur="7">loved this country so much that they’d risk
everything to realize its promise.</text><text start="1506.789" dur="7">That’s what it means to love America. That’s
what it means to believe in America. That’s</text><text start="1515.549" dur="7">what it means when we say America is exceptional.
For we were born of change. We broke the old</text><text start="1524.499" dur="5.4">aristocracies, declaring ourselves entitled
not by bloodline, but endowed by our Creator</text><text start="1529.899" dur="7">with certain unalienable rights. We secure
our rights and responsibilities through a</text><text start="1537.049" dur="7">system of self-government, of and by and for
the people. That’s why we argue and fight</text><text start="1544.109" dur="6.25">with so much passion and conviction, because
we know our efforts matter. We know America</text><text start="1550.359" dur="7">is what we make of it.
We are Lewis and Clark and Sacajawea – pioneers</text><text start="1561.529" dur="7">who braved the unfamiliar, followed by a stampede
of farmers and miners, entrepreneurs and hucksters.</text><text start="1569.84" dur="7">That’s our spirit.
We are Sojourner Truth and Fannie Lou Hamer,</text><text start="1577.409" dur="5.23">women who could do as much as any man and
then some; and we’re Susan B. Anthony, who</text><text start="1582.639" dur="5.12">shook the system until the law reflected that
truth. That’s our character.</text><text start="1587.759" dur="5.92">We’re the immigrants who stowed away on
ships to reach these shores, the huddled masses</text><text start="1593.679" dur="7">yearning to breathe free – Holocaust survivors,
Soviet defectors, the Lost Boys of Sudan.</text><text start="1601.539" dur="7">We are the hopeful strivers who cross the
Rio Grande because they want their kids to</text><text start="1608.7" dur="4.39">know a better life. That’s how we came to
be.</text><text start="1613.09" dur="6.309">We’re the slaves who built the White House
and the economy of the South. We’re the</text><text start="1619.399" dur="5.66">ranch hands and cowboys who opened the West,
and countless laborers who laid rail, and</text><text start="1625.059" dur="4.11">raised skyscrapers, and organized for workers’
rights.</text><text start="1629.169" dur="7">We’re the fresh-faced GIs who fought to
liberate a continent, and we’re the Tuskeegee</text><text start="1636.289" dur="6.59">Airmen, Navajo code-talkers, and Japanese-Americans
who fought for this country even as their</text><text start="1642.879" dur="7">own liberty had been denied. We’re the firefighters
who rushed into those buildings on 9/11, and</text><text start="1651.21" dur="4.579">the volunteers who signed up to fight in Afghanistan
and Iraq.</text><text start="1655.789" dur="5.31">We are the gay Americans whose blood ran on
the streets of San Francisco and New York,</text><text start="1661.099" dur="6.39">just as blood ran down this bridge.
We are storytellers, writers, poets, and artists</text><text start="1667.489" dur="6.77">who abhor unfairness, and despise hypocrisy,
and give voice to the voiceless, and tell</text><text start="1674.259" dur="6.571">truths that need to be told.
We are the inventors of gospel and jazz and</text><text start="1680.83" dur="5.899">the blues, bluegrass and country, hip-hop
and rock and roll, our very own sounds with</text><text start="1686.729" dur="7">all the sweet sorrow and reckless joy of freedom.
We are Jackie Robinson, enduring scorn and</text><text start="1694.099" dur="4.861">spiked cleats and pitches coming straight
to his head, and stealing home in the World</text><text start="1698.96" dur="7">Series anyway.
We are the people Langston Hughes wrote of,</text><text start="1706.08" dur="6.99">who “build our temples for tomorrow, strong
as we know how.”</text><text start="1713.07" dur="5.279">We are the people Emerson wrote of, “who
for truth and honor’s sake stand fast and</text><text start="1718.349" dur="4.111">suffer long;” who are “never tired, so
long as we can see far enough.”</text><text start="1722.46" dur="7">That’s what America is. Not stock photos
or airbrushed history or feeble attempts to</text><text start="1733.45" dur="7">define some of us as more American as others.
We respect the past, but we don’t pine for</text><text start="1747.109" dur="7">it. We don’t fear the future; we grab for
it. America is not some fragile thing; we</text><text start="1758.479" dur="6.221">are large, in the words of Whitman, containing
multitudes. We are boisterous and diverse</text><text start="1764.7" dur="5.929">and full of energy, perpetually young in spirit.
That’s why someone like John Lewis at the</text><text start="1770.629" dur="7">ripe age of 25 could lead a mighty march.
And that’s what the young people here today</text><text start="1778.499" dur="7">and listening all across the country must
take away from this day. You are America.</text><text start="1788.739" dur="7">Unconstrained by habits and convention. Unencumbered
by what is, and ready to seize what ought</text><text start="1796.859" dur="7">to be. For everywhere in this country, there
are first steps to be taken, and new ground</text><text start="1805.299" dur="7">to cover, and bridges to be crossed. And it
is you, the young and fearless at heart, the</text><text start="1815.139" dur="7">most diverse and educated generation in our
history, who the nation is waiting to follow.</text><text start="1823.33" dur="7">Because Selma shows us that America is not
the project of any one person.</text><text start="1830.529" dur="7">Because the single most powerful word in our
democracy is the word “We.” We The People.</text><text start="1840.859" dur="7">We Shall Overcome. Yes We Can. It is owned
by no one. It belongs to everyone. Oh, what</text><text start="1853.219" dur="7">a glorious task we are given, to continually
try to improve this great nation of ours.</text><text start="1864.07" dur="6.969">Fifty years from Bloody Sunday, our march
is not yet finished. But we are getting closer.</text><text start="1871.039" dur="4.94">Two hundred and thirty-nine years after this
nation’s founding, our union is not yet</text><text start="1875.979" dur="6.74">perfect. But we are getting closer. Our job’s
easier because somebody already got us through</text><text start="1882.719" dur="7">that first mile. Somebody already got us over
that bridge. When it feels the road’s too</text><text start="1890.07" dur="7">hard, when the torch we’ve been passed feels
too heavy, we will remember these early travelers,</text><text start="1897.32" dur="5.229">and draw strength from their example, and
hold firmly the words of the prophet Isaiah:</text><text start="1902.549" dur="6.75">“Those who hope in the Lord will renew their
strength. They will soar on wings like eagles.</text><text start="1909.299" dur="5">They will run and not grow weary. They will
walk and not be faint.”</text><text start="1914.299" dur="7">We honor those who walked so we could run.
We must run so our children soar. And we will</text><text start="1922.089" dur="5.18">not grow weary. For we believe in the power
of an awesome God, and we believe in this</text><text start="1927.269" dur="4.671">country’s sacred promise.
May He bless those warriors of justice no</text><text start="1931.94" dur="3.4">longer with us, and bless the United States
of America.</text></transcript>